tribute.ca 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy | Tribute.ca

**PRIVACY POLICY**

This website, available at www.tribute.ca (“Website”), is owned and operated by Tribute Publishing Inc. (“Tribute”, “we”, “us”, “our”). We have prepared this Privacy Policy to describe the manner in which we collect, use, disclose and otherwise manage personal information collected through the Website. 

**COLLECTION & USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

The term “personal information” means information about an identifiable individual, including name, address, email address, and other information relating to an individual. 

We collect personal information when you: 

  * Subscribe to receive email, SMS text messages or other communications; 
  * Enter into a contest or promotion; 
  * Participate in one of our surveys or other polls or customer research; 
  * Use the invite-a-friend or similar feature on our Website; 
  * Make a purchase or donation; 
  * Post a comment, rating or review on our Website; or 
  * Contact us with an idea, question, comment or complaint. 

**Communications:** From time to time, we may collect certain personal information (such as first and last name, email address) to send you email, SMS text messages or other communications that may be of interest to you, such as the MOVIE MAIL newsletter or other offers from us or our partners. We may also collect optional information such as your age and/or gender in order to tailor our communications to you. You may remove yourself from our or our Tribute Partners’ e-mail lists by following the unsubscribe instructions in each of the e-mails. If you have signed up to receive SMS text messages, you may opt out by following the opt-out instructions provided in your SMS messages. You may also remove yourself from our list by contacting us as set out in the “How to Contact Us” section below. 

**Contests and Promotions:** When you enter a contest or participate in a promotion, we may collect your name, address, phone number, email address, age, gender and other information you provide. We use this information to administer your participation in the contest or promotion. At the time you enter the contest or promotion, we may obtain your consent to add you to our email or other marketing list. If a contest or promotion is jointly sponsored by us and one or more sponsors, your personal information may be shared with such sponsors, as specified at the time of collection of your personal information. We do not control the use, disclosure or security of your personal information by other sponsors, and recommend you review their respective privacy notices or statements. 

**Surveys, Polls and Customer Research:** From time to time, we may offer you the opportunity to participate in one of our surveys, polls or other customer research. The information obtained through our surveys and customer research is used in an aggregated form. We use this information to help us understand visitors to our site and/or to enhance our product and service offerings, promotions and events. 

**Invite-a-Friend and Similar Sharing Features:** The “Invite a Friend” and other similar features on our Website permit you to send email to others. This feature requires you to submit your name and email address, as well as the name and email address of the recipient. We do not use the names or email addresses submitted in these circumstances for any other purpose without the consent of you or the email recipient to do so. Please ensure that you only submit email addresses of friends or family that would like to receive the email. 

**Purchases and Donations:** When you make a purchase or donation, we collect certain personal information such as your first and last name, mailing and billing address, email address, phone number and payment card-related information. We use this information to process and administer your payment or donation, and to fulfill your order. When you make a purchase, we may also ask for optional information such as your age and gender. We use this information to personalize your experience. 

**Comments, Ratings & Reviews: ** When you post a message on our Website forums, such as by commenting on a news story or posting a rating or review, you may be asked for personal information such as your name and email address. We collect this information to identify who you are and to facilitate your participation in our forums. Please remember that any information you disclose in these public forums becomes public information and is immediately accessible to other users, so it is important for you to carefully consider what, if any, personal information you reveal in these areas. 

**Feedback, Questions and Comments:** If you choose to contact us with feedback or a comment, question or complaint, we collect your name **,** e-mail address and your feedback, comment, question or complaint you provide. We use this information to respond to you and may retain this information to assist you in the future. We also may use your feedback, comments, questions or complaints to monitor and/or improve our product and service offerings and our Website. 

**WEBSITE INFORMATION**

In general, you can visit our Website without telling us who you are or submitting any personal information. However, we collect the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to our Website and other related information such as page requests, browser type, operating system, and average time spent on our Website. We use this information to help us understand Website activity and to monitor and improve our services and our Website. 

**Cookies & Other Technologies** : Our Website uses a technology called "cookies". A cookie is a tiny element of data that our Website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so we can recognize you when you return. We use cookies to help us understand which areas of our Website are useful and which areas need improvement. You may set your Web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to not accept certain cookies. However, if you decide not to accept cookies from our Website, you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the features of our Website. 

Our Website may also use a technology called "tracer tags" or "Web Beacons". This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on our Website. These tracer tags are used to help us optimize and tailor our Website for you and other future visitors to our Website. 

**Tailored Ads:** We use remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show ads for Tribute on websites across the internet. We and our third-party vendors, including Google and DoubleClick, use cookies to inform, optimize, and serve ads on our Website and on third-party websites based on your past visits to our Website. These cookies may also be used to report on ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services related to visits to our Website. 

You can choose not to receive tailored advertising from Google using [ Google’s Ad settings ](https://www.google.com/settings/ads?hl=en) and from other third-party vendors listed on this [online tool](http://youradchoices.ca/choices). If you opt out of receiving tailored advertising from these third-parties, you may still see Tribute ads on other websites, but those ads will not be customized by the companies that you opt-out of and Tribute may continue to customize your experience on our website using cookies. 

**SOCIAL MEDIA**

We may offer you the opportunity to engage with our content on or through third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, such as when you share a movie trailer or screening information. When you engage with our content on or through third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, you may allow us to have access to certain information associated with your social media account (e.g., name, username, email address, profile picture, gender) to deliver the content or as part of the operation of the website, plug-in or application. When you provide information from your social media account, we may use this information to personalize your experience on our Website and on the third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, and to provide you with other products or services you may request. 

**DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We will not disclose, trade, rent, sell or otherwise transfer your personal information without your consent, except as otherwise set out herein. 

**Service Providers** : We may transfer (or otherwise make available) your personal information to third parties who provide services on our behalf. For example, we may use service providers host our Website, operate certain of its features, serve advertisements on our Website, process and administer donations, send email, SMS text messages or other communications, run our contests and promotions, and analyze data and our advertising effectiveness. 

Your personal information may be maintained and processed by our affiliates and other third party service providers in the US or other jurisdictions. Our service providers are given the information they need to perform their designated functions, and we do not authorize them to use or disclose personal information for their own marketing or other purposes. For additional information about the manner in which our service providers treat your personal information, contact us as set out below. 

**Legal** : We and our Canadian and US **** affiliates and third party service providers may provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid enquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable Canadian, US or other law. We may also disclose personal information where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims or prevent actual or suspect loss or harm to persons or property. 

**Sale of a Business:** We may transfer any information we have about you as an asset in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of Tribute or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control. 

**LINKS**

Our Website may contain links to other sites that we do not own or operate, including our third party sponsors or partners which may include a reference to Tribute Publishing Inc. or a Tribute logo as part of a co-branding agreement. Also, links to our Website may be featured on third party websites on which we advertise. Except as provided herein, we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your consent. We provide links to third party websites as a convenience to the user. These links are not intended as an endorsement of or referral to the linked websites. The linked websites have separate and independent privacy statements, notices and terms of use, which we recommend you read carefully. We do not have any control over such websites, and therefore we have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use or disclose, secure and otherwise treat your personal information. 

**SAFEGUARDS**

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control. 

**RETENTION**

We have personal information retention processes designed to retain personal information of our customers for no longer than necessary for the purposes stated above or to otherwise meet legal requirements. 

**ACCESS TO PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You have the right to access, update, and correct inaccuracies in your personal information in our custody and control, subject to limited exceptions prescribed by law. You may request access, updating and corrections of inaccuracies in the personal information we have in our custody or control by contacting us as set out under “Contact Us” below. We may request certain personal information for the purposes of verifying your identity when requesting access to or correction of your personal information records. 

**CHANGES**

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically to reflect changes to our personal information practices. The revised Privacy Notice will be posted on the Website. We strongly encourage you to please refer to this Privacy Policy often for the latest information about our personal information practices. 

**CONTACT US**

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or the manner in which we or our service providers treat your personal information, please contact our **Privacy Officer** at the following information: [**generalinfo@tribute.ca**](mailto:generalinfo@tribute.ca)

* * *

Last updated: January 29, 2014
